Ira Eaker Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Scheduling File, 1952-1982 (Box II:66-87)
  - 1979
    - 24 Sept., Sir John Slessor memorial service, London, England
    - 2 Oct., United States Strategic Institute (USSI) board meeting, Washington, D.C.
    - 5 Oct., Aviation/Space Writers Association, reception for Robert B. Hotz, Washington, D.C.
    - 10 Oct., Sylvanus Thayer Award ceremonies, United States Military Academy, West Point, N.Y.
    - 7 Nov., DC-3 model dedication, International Club, Washington, D.C.
    - 9 Nov., Air Force Association dinner, Andrews Air Force Base, Washington, D.C.
    - 6 Dec., Tuskegee Airmen Distinguished Achievement Award ceremonies, Beverly Hills, Calif.
    - 10 Dec., Squadron Officer School, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 14 Dec., Wright Memorial dinner, Washington, D.C.
  - 1980
    - 22 Feb., James A. Hill reception and dinner, Bolling Air Force Base, Washington, D.C.
    - 3-5 Mar., Air University, Airpower Symposium, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 11 Mar., Industrial College of the Armed Forces, Washington, D.C.
    - 12-14 Mar., Air Force Logistics Command (AFLC) Commanders' Conference, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio
    - 17 Mar., Squadron Officer School, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 11 Apr., birthday luncheon hosted by David C. Jones
    - 15 Apr., birthday luncheon hosted by Jennings Randolph
    - 19-20 Apr., 8th Air Force prisoner of war reunion, Cincinnati, Ohio
    - 19 Apr., Bomber Command reunion dinner honoring Sir Arthur T. Harris, London, England
    - 1 May, Senior Statesmen Symposium, Washington, D.C.
    - 22 May, American Eagle awards, Washington, D.C.
    - 27 May, Carbao luncheon, Washington, D.C.
    - 29 May, Squadron Officer School, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 4-13 June, European trip
    - 26 June, William A. Knowlton retirement ceremony, Fort Meyer, Va.
    - 28 June, salute to Carl A. Spaatz, Boyertown, Pa.
    - 9-10 Sept., Air War College, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 15 Sept., Squadron Officer School, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 18 Sept., Commonwealth Wartime Aircrew reunion, Winnipeg, Canada
    - 1-3 Oct., Military History Symposium, Air Force Academy, Colorado Springs, Colo.
    - 6-9 Oct., Air Force Logistics Command "Rebluing '80," Kelly Air Force Base, Tex.
    - 30 Nov.-1 Dec., Squadron Officer School, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
    - 13 Dec., Embry-Riddle Aeronautical University, Daytona Beach, Fla.
  - 1981
    - 19-22 Jan., Howard Hughes Memorial Award, ceremonies in honor of Lawrence A. Hyland, Marina del Ray, Calif.
    - 23-25 Feb., Air University Airpower Symposium, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala.
  - 1982
    - 1 May, Bomber Command reunion dinner, London, England
- Part II: Speeches and Writings File, 1929-1981 (Box II:88-114)
  Articles, book reviews, forewords, columns, speeches, speech material, and various other writings.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Articles (Box II:88)
    - 1954-1980, undated, (24 folders)
    - Miscellaneous published articles, 1931, 1972-1981
  - Book reviews, 1962-1979, (25 folders) (Box II:89)
  - Columns
    - List 1962-1974
    - Jan. 1962-June 1963, (11 folders)
    - July 1963-Oct. 1964, (16 folders) (Box II:90)
    - Nov. 1964-Feb. 1966, (16 folders) (Box II:91)
    - Mar. 1966-Mar. 1967, (13 folders) (Box II:92)
    - Apr. 1967-Mar. 1968, (12 folders) (Box II:93)
    - Apr. 1968-July 1969, (16 folders) (Box II:94)
    - Aug. 1969-Oct. 1970, (15 folders) (Box II:95)
    - Nov. 1970-Oct. 1971, (13 folders) (Box II:96)
    - Nov. 1971-May 1973, (19 folders) (Box II:97)
    - June 1973-Apr. 1974, (11 folders) (Box II:98)
    - May 1974-Mar. 1975, (11 folders) (Box II:99)
    - Apr. 1975-Feb. 1976, (11 folders) (Box II:100)
    - Mar.-Dec. 1976, (10 folders) (Box II:101)
    - Jan.-Oct. 1977, (10 folders) (Box II:102)
    - Nov. 1977-Sept. 1978, (11 folders) (Box II:103)
    - Oct. 1978-July 1979, (10 folders) (Box II:104)
    - Aug. 1979-June 1980, (11 folders) (Box II:105)
    - July-Dec. 1980, (6 folders) (Box II:106)
  - Column correspondence
    - General Features Corp.
      - Commission analysis, 1967-1974, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1967-1970, (2 folders)
        - 1971-1974 (Box II:107)
    - Response to columns, 1967-1980, (2 folders)
  - Column miscellaneous, 1961-1974, undated
  - Forewords
    - 1962-1975, (8 folders)
    - 1977-1980, undated, (9 folders) (Box II:108)
  - Speeches
    - List, 1946-1958
    - Texts
      - Jan. 1946-Dec. 1963, (6 folders)
      - Feb. 1964-Sept. 1968, (7 folders) (Box II:109)
      - Dec. 1968-July 1973, (7 folders) (Box II:110)
      - Oct. 1973-Mar. 1976, (6 folders) (Box II:111)
      - June 1976-Jan. 1981, (4 folders) (Box II:112)
      - Undated and unidentified
  - Speech material
    - Sept. 1947-Dec. 1952
    - Jan. 1953-Aug. 1962, (7 folders) (Box II:113)
    - Sept. 1962-Sept. 1963, 1976 (Box II:114)
    - Humor, anecdotes, and quotations, 1963-1979, undated
  - Various other writings
    - 1929-1974, undated, (19 folders)
    - Unidentified
- Part II: Subject File, 1927-1985 (Box II:114-149)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial data, clippings, printed matter, and miscellaneous material.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization, or topic.
  - Admiral Nimitz Foundation, 1973-1979, undated (Box II:114)
  - Aerospace Industries Association, 1960-1979, (8 folders) (Box II:115)
  - Air and Space Museum, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1978
  - Air force, 1959-1981, undated, (8 folders) (Box II:116)
  - Air Force Academy
    - 1960-1964, (2 folders)
    - 1965-1980 See also Oversize, (10 folders) (Box II:117)
  - Air Force Academy Foundation
    - 1962-1971
    - 1972-1978 (Box II:118)
  - Air Force Association, 1962-1980, (4 folders)
  - Air Force Historical Foundation
    - Aerospace Historian
      - Nov. 1965-June 1971, (2 folders)
      - July 1971-Apr. 1979, (2 folders) (Box II:119)
    - Board of Trustees, 1960-1980, undated, (6 folders)
  - Air Force Logistics Command (AFLC), 1962-1978 (Box II:120)
  - Air Force Museum and Foundation, 1964-1976
  - "Air Force Policy Letter for Commanders," 15 Oct. 1962-15 Dec. 1971, 1 Dec. 1979-1 Oct. 1980, (3 folders)
  - "Air Force Policy Letter for Commanders," Supplement, 1974, 1980, (2 folders)
  - Air Force Systems Command, 1973-1976
  - American Cause, 1974-1978
  - American Defense Preparedness Association, 1962-1974
  - American Fighter Aces Association, 1965-1967 (Box II:121)
  - American Legion, 1961-1978, (3 folders)
  - American Memorials and Overseas Cemeteries, 1967-1970
  - American Ordnance Association, 1960-1961
  - American Security Council, 1973-1978
  - American Society of the French Legion of Honor, 1948-1951
  - Appointments and telephone messages, 1960-1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - Armed Forces Network in Europe, July 1972 (Box II:122)
  - Arms of Friendship, Inc., 1958-1965, (6 folders)
  - Army, 1960-1962, undated
  - Army and Navy Club, Washington, D.C., 1958-1981, (2 folders)
  - Arnold, Henry Harley ("Hap"), biography, 1957-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box II:123)
  - Arvida Corp., 1959-1962
  - Association of the U.S. Army, 1969-1981, (2 folders)
  - Aviation
    - Boeing-Hornet Shuttle transcontinental refueling experiment, 1930, undated
    - History, 1977-1978
    - Pan-American Goodwill Flight of 1926-1927, 1927, 1976-1986
    - “Question Mark” Flight (Box II:124)
      - Flight log, 1929
      - General, 1929-1979, undated
      - Report, 1929, (2 folders)
    - Transcontinental blind flight, 1936, 1980
  - Aviation Hall of Fame, 1962-1980
  - Aviation technology
    - Lear jet, 1963-1964
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1975, undated
  - Battle of Britain Museum, London, England, 1977-1978
  - Bel-Air Country Club, Los Angeles, Calif., 1950-1962
  - Belding, Don, 1953, 1967-1969, (2 folders) (Box II:125)
  - Beverly Hills Wine and Food Society, Beverly Hills, Calif., 1951, 1960-1963
  - Beverly Hills Club, Beverly Hills, Calif., 1957, 1963
  - Biographical information
    - General, 1929-1980, undated
    - Honors and awards, 1930-1979 See also Part II: Oversize
    - Oral History interviews
      - For "Air Force Now" film, includes Carl A. Spaatz, Apr. 1972
      - With Walter Bonney, 11 Feb. 1974
      - With Thomas M. Coffey, Apr. 1975
    - Personal records, 1947-1978, undated
    - Promotion ceremony, 1985
  - Bolling Field, Washington, D.C., 1962, undated
  - Bostain, James, 1974
  - British United Services Club, Los Angeles, Calif., 1951-1959
  - Brown, George S., 1973-1976
  - Burning Tree Country Club, Bethesda, Md., 1958-1972, (2 folders)
  - Caradja, Catherine, 1973-1977 (Box II:126)
  - Chevy Chase Club, Chevy Chase, Md., 1959-1973, (2 folders)
  - China, 1971-1976, undated
  - Churchill, Winston (1874-1965), 1971-1977
  - City Tavern Association, Washington, D.C., 1960-1967
  - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1960
  - Clippings
    - Miscellaneous, 1966-1980, undated
    - World War II, 1942-1979, undated
  - Coffey, Thomas M., 1973-1979 For additional material see Container II:125, Biographical information, and Container II:128, Decision Over Schweinfurt
  - Committee on the Present Danger, 1976-1980 (Box II:127)
  - Confrerie des Chevaliers du Tastevin, Los Angeles, Calif., chapter, 1955-1962
  - Congress, 1960-1961
  - Congressional Record, 1975-1980
  - Currey, John Causten, 1965-1969, (2 folders)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1971-1980
  - Davis, Jacquelyn K., 1977-1979, (2 folders)
  - Decision Over Schweinfurt, 1977-1979, (2 folders) (Box II:128)
  - Defense Department, 1959-1980, undated
  - Defense Orientation Conference Association, 1961-1971, (3 folders)
  - Doolittle, James H., 1979
  - Dougherty, Russell E., 1974-1978
  - Douglas, Donald W. (1892-1981), 1958-1961
  - Douglas, Donald W. (1917- ), 1954-1962 (Box II:129)
  - Dresden, Germany, bombing raids, 1977-1978
  - Ducks Unlimited, Inc., 1965-1969
  - Eaker Field, Durant, Okla., 1972-1974, undated
  - Eighth Air Force Historical Society, 1970-1981, undated
  - English-Speaking Union
    - 1963-1968, (3 folders)
    - 1969-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box II:130)
  - Falcon Foundation
    - July 1958-Dec. 1966, (5 folders)
    - June 1967-Sept. 1973, (6 folders) (Box II:131)
    - Oct. 1973-May 1979, (3 folders) (Box II:132)
  - Federal Aviation Agency, 1960-1961
  - Ford, Gerald R., 1974-1976
  - "Fortress," 1980, undated
  - Generals, 1938-1972, undated, (2 folders)
  - George, Harold L., 1959-1965, undated
  - George C. Marshall Research Library, Lexington, Va., 1964-1969
  - Goldwater, Barry M., 1973-1979
  - Hall of Fame for Great Americans, New York, N.Y., 1965, undated (Box II:133)
  - Hansell, Haywood S., 1972-1980, (6 folders)
  - Harman, Phillip
    - 1969-1971
    - 1972-1976, (3 folders) (Box II:134)
  - Harris, Arthur, 1947, 1976-1979, undated
  - Henley, Nadine, 1975-1979
  - Hinshaw, Bill, 1955
  - Holloway, Bruce K., 1971-1980, (2 folders)
  - Hotz, Robert B., 1974
  - Hughes Aircraft Company, 1948-1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box II:135)
  - Hughes, Howard R., Jr., estate litigation, 1977-1981 For additional material see Container II:134, Henley, Nadine
  - Huglin, Henry, 1972-1976, undated
  - Impact: The Army Air Forces' Confidential Picture History of World War II, 1978-1980 (Box II:136)
  - Ira C. Eaker essay award, Air University, Maxwell Air Force Base, Ala., 1979, undated
  - Ira C. Eaker Distinguished Lecture on National Defense Policy, United States Air Force Academy, Colorado Springs, Colo., 1978-1980
  - Jackson, Henry M., 1972-1979, undated
  - JANUS Engineering Designs
    - Jan.-July 1962, (2 folders)
    - Aug. 1962-Dec. 1966, (7 folders) (Box II:137)
    - Jan. 1967-Jan. 1969 (Box II:138)
  - Johnson & Johnson, 1962-1965
  - Jones, David C., 1980, undated
  - Keegan, George J., 1973-1977, (2 folders)
  - King and Queen Rod and Gun Club, Stevensville, Va., 1960-1973, (2 folders)
  - LeMay, Curtis E., 1965, 1978-1979
  - Library of Congress, 1950-1979, (2 folders) (Box II:139)
  - Lincoln, Franklin B., Jr., 1968-1969
  - Lindbergh, Charles A., 1949, 1975-1977, undated
  - Los Angeles Independent Publishing Co., 1948-1949, undated
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1978-1981, undated
  - McGovern, George, war record, 1972
  - McHugh, Ray, 1973-1977
  - Metcalf, Arthur B., "On War Deterrence," 1976, (2 folders)
  - Metropolitan Club, Washington, D.C., 1958-1971 (Box II:140)
  - Metropolitan Washington Board of Trade, Washington, D.C., 1959-1964
  - Mihajlovic, Draza, 1974
  - Military compensation and retirement, 1975-1978, undated
  - Military Order of the Carabao, 1956-1979, undated
  - Military Order of the World Wars, 1951-1974, undated
  - Military personnel studies, 1972, undated
  - Military technology, 1969-1980, undated
  - Miscellany, 1944-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:141)
  - Monte Cassino, Italy, 1965-1975, undated
  - National Aeronautic Association, 1967-1979, (2 folders)
  - National Defense Transportation Association, 1958-1976
  - National Press Club, Washington, D.C., 1955-1964
  - National Rocket Club, 1958-1960
  - National Security Act of 1947, 1977
  - National Security Agency, 1975
  - National security miscellany
    - Oct. 1947-Mar. 1977
    - Aug. 1977-Jan. 1980, undated (Box II:142)
  - Navy, 1961-1976, (2 folders)
  - Net Assessment Task Force, 1975
  - Nineteen Twenty-Five F Street Club, Washington, D.C., 1958-1963
  - Ninety-first Bomb Group (H) Association, 1967-1978
  - Ninety-fourth Bomb Group Memorial Association, 1974-1978
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization, 1972-1980
  - Order of Daedalians
    - 1948-1961, (2 folders)
    - 1962-1978, (2 folders) (Box II:143)
  - Organizational memberships, 1950-1968
  - Overkill, 1963-circa 1965
  - Panama, 1973-1979 For additional material see Containers II:133-134, Harman, Phillip, (2 folders)
  - Pawley, William D., 1963, 1973-1977, (2 folders)
  - Philippine bases treaty, 1979 (Box II:144)
  - Portugal, undated
  - President's Committee on Employment of the Handicapped, 1960-1977, (3 folders)
  - Prisoners of war, 1972-1974
  - Retired Officers Association, 1949-1974
  - Rhodesia, 1966-1979
  - Rogue River, Oreg., 1975
  - Russia
    - 1967-1973
    - 1974-1981, undated, (3 folders) (Box II:145)
  - Second Schweinfurt Memorial Association, 1976-1979
  - Silber, John R., 1979
  - Simulmatics Corp., 1962-1967
  - Sino-Soviet conflict, 1967
  - Society of Experimental Test Pilots, 1966, 1975-1979
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr I., 1975 (Box II:146)
  - Southeast Asia, 1963-1975, undated
  - Spaatz, Carl A., 1944, 1955-1979, undated
  - Space, 1965-1980, undated, (2 folders)
  - Speer, Albert, 1976-1977, undated
  - Strategic Air Command (SAC) press service, 1978-1980
  - Strategic Arms Limitation Talks (SALT), 1970-1980, undated, (6 folders) (Box II:147)
  - Sulzberger, C. L., 1972-1978
  - Susskind, Harold A.
    - Dec. 1967-May 1970
    - June 1970-July 1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box II:148)
  - Sweden, 1976-1978, undated
  - Symington, Stuart W., 1947-1950, 1969
  - Tactical Air Command, 1977-1980, undated
  - Tax credit for higher education, 1955-1957, undated
  - Think tanks,1965-1968
  - Three Hundred Nineteenth Bombardment Group, 1978
  - Thunderbolt P-47 Pilots Association, 1968-1974
  - Ultra Secret, 1974, undated
  - U.S.S.R. See Containers II: 144-145, Russia
  - Unionization of the military, 1975-1978, undated
  - United Nations, 1969-1974
  - United States Strategic Bombing Survey, 1945
  - United States Strategic Institute, Washington, D.C., 1978-1979
  - Vandenberg, Hoyt S., 1949-1952 (Box II:149)
  - War Control Planners, Inc., 1969-1973
  - Warnke, Paul C., 1972, undated
  - Watergate affair, 1973
  - Weather, undated
  - West Lane Keys house, Washington, D.C., 1958-1962
  - Women in the military, 1972-1977, undated
  - World Bank, 1978
  - Wycombe Abbey School Foundation, 1960-1961
  - XB-70 accident, 1966
  - Yorty, Sam, 1961, 1967-1971, (2 folders)
  - Yugoslavia, 1969-1976
- Part II: James Parton File, 1917-1989 (Box II:149-150)
  Correspondence and book reviews relating to Parton's biography of Eaker, Air Force Spoken Here, and correspondence from the last years of Eaker's life, much relating to the disposition of his medals, trophies, and uniforms, and a master's thesis on Eaker.
  Arranged alphabetically by topic and chronologically therein.
  - "Air Force Spoken Here" (Box II:149)
    - Book reviews, 1986-1987
    - Correspondence
      - 1917, 1943, 1983
      - 1931-1966, 1984
      - 1985-1987, (2 folders) (Box II:150)
  - Disposition of medals, uniforms, and other memorabilia
    - Correspondence, 1983-1989, (2 folders)
    - Inventory of medals, trophies, and memorabilia, 1985
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-1988, (2 folders)
  - Sears, Betty M., Masters thesis, "General Ira C. Eaker: Oklahoma's Pioneer Aviator," 1979
- Part II: Oversize, 1930-1967 (Box II:OV 1)
  Drawings, blueprints, and certificates.
  - Part II: Scheduling File (Box II:OV 1)
    - 1967
      - 31 Mar.- 2 Apr.
        - Air Force Academy meeting re cemetery gate, Colorado Springs, Colo., undated (Container II:73)
  - Part II: Subject File
    - Air Force Academy, circa 1967 (Container II:117)
    - Biographical information
      - Honors and awards, 1930, 1945 (Container II:125)
- Part II: Classified, 1952-1978 (Box II:CL 1)
  - General Correspondence (Box II:CL 1)
    - 19 Nov. 1952 (Container II:7)
    - 10 Nov. 1975 (Container II:49)
  - Scheduling File
    - 1967
      - 14-15 Aug., Air Force Logistics Command (AFLC) Commanders' Conference, Wright-Patterson Air Force Base, Ohio (Container II:73)
  - Subject File
    - Defense Department, 1977-1978, undated (Container II:128)